http://www.dot.ca.gov/conditions-of-use

HomeConditions of Use
Conditions of Use
Thank you for visiting the Caltrans Office web site and reviewing our Use Policy. You should also be aware that the State has a Privacy Policy, also available on this web site. The State wants you to know about the collection, use, security, and access to information that may be obtained through use of the State's web portal. By visiting this web site, you are accepting the policies and practices described in this Notice.
Please note that this Use Policy is subject to change without notice, and that it reflects the State's current business practices. This Use policy is dated December 7, 2000.
Also note that each department within the State may have additional privacy and use policies specific to the mission and needs of their work. Be sure to review those policies as you access additional sites within the State.
Personal Information and Choice
"Personal information" is information about a natural person that identifies or describes an individual, including, but not limited to, his or her name, social security number, physical description, home address, home telephone number, education, financial matters, and medical or employment history, readily identifiable to that specific individual. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information, however, it is considered
"electronically collected personal information."
According to Government Code § 11015.5., "electronically collected personal information" means any information that is maintained by an agency that identifies or describes an individual user, including, but not limited to, his or her name, social security number, physical description, home address, home telephone number, education, financial matters, medical or employment history, password, electronic mail address, and information that reveals any network location or identity, but excludes any information manually submitted to a State agency by a user, whether electronically or in written form, and information on or relating to individuals who are users, serving in a business capacity, including, but not limited to, business owners, officers, or principals of that business.
Under Government Code § 11015.5., if you choose, you may have any personal information collected about you discarded without reuse or distribution, provided we are contacted in a timely fashion.
"Electronically collected personal information" that we automatically
collect includes your domain name or Internet Protocol address, and statistical
information about which web pages you visit. If you voluntarily participate
in an activity that asks for specific information (i.e., completing a request
for assistance, personalizing the content of the web site, sending an e-mail,
or participating in a survey) more detailed data will be collected. If
you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will in
no way affect your ability to use any other feature of the web site.
If any type of personal information is requested on the web site or volunteered
by the user, State law, including the Information Practices Act of 1977,
Government Code Section 11015.5., and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may
protect it. However, this information may be a public record once you provide
it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not otherwise
protected by federal or State law.
Additionally, departments and agencies of the State of California under
the authority of the Governor are required to adhere to the Privacy Policy
which is also accessible on this web site.
A Special Note About Children
Children are not eligible to use services that require submission of personal
information, and we require that minors (under the age of 18) do not submit
any personal information to us. This includes submitting personal information
to the State as part of a user profile or personalization profile. If you
are a minor, you can use these services only if used together with your
parents or guardians. If you are a minor, you should seek guidance from
your parents.
If the State decides to begin collecting personal information from children,
it will notify parents that it is being requested, disclose the reasons
for collecting it, and disclose our intended use of it. The State will
seek parental consent before collecting any personally identifiable information.
If it does collect it, parents may request information on the type of data
being collected, view their child's information, and, if they choose, prohibit
the State from making further use of their child's information. The State
will not provide personal information about children to third parties.
Information Collected and How it is Used
We do collect personal information directly from individuals who volunteer
to use some of our services. Collection of this information is required
to deliver the specific services, but use of these services is voluntary.
If you do nothing during your visit to the web site but browse or download
information, we automatically collect and store the following information
about your visit:
The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used, but not the e-mail
address. The Internet Protocol Address is a numerical identifier assigned
either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer.
We use the Internet Protocol Address to direct Internet traffic to you
and generate statistics used in the management of this site;
The type of browser and operating system you used;
The date and time you visited this site;
The web pages or services you accessed at this site;
The web site you visited prior to coming to this web site;
The web site you visit as you leave this web site; and
If you downloaded a form, the form that was downloaded.
The information we automatically collect or store is used to improve the
content of our web services and to help us understand how people are using
our services. This information does not identify you personally and is
used for gathering web site statistics. The information we automatically
collect and store in our logs about your visit helps us to analyze our
web site to continually improve the value of the materials available. Our
web site logs do not identify a visitor by personal information, and we
make no attempt to link other web sites with the individuals that browse
the State's web site.
Government Code § 11015.5.(a)(6) prohibits all state agencies from
distributing or selling any electronically collected personal information,
as defined above, about users to any third party without the permission
of the user. The State does not sell any "electronically collected
personal information." Any distribution of "electronically collected
personal information" will be solely for the purposes for which it
was provided to us.
The State may provide or distribute certain lists and statistical reports
of regulatory information as provided by law, but no personal information
is sold or distributed, and all relevant legal protections still apply
to the State's web sites.
What Happens to Information You Submit to Us?
If you choose to submit information to us, the information will be transmitted
through secure lines to our departmental database. Any private information
will only be used for the purposes for which it was provided and will not
be shared with another entity except as prescribed by law. Please see our
Privacy Policy for additional information.
Use of Internet Request for Assistance From Information
Any information you provide to us will only be shared with entities involved
in your case as necessary. Information you provide may be included with
other consumers' information to be used for statistical reporting, trending
data, and/or investigative actions. For example, we may need to retain
information that becomes part of an enforcement action or consumer complaint
case for a period of time after the closing date of the case.
If you provide us with information regarding an issue that does not fall
within our regulatory jurisdiction, we may refer your information to the
appropriate local, State, or federal agency on your behalf.
Surveys
If during your visit to the State's web site you participate in a survey
or send an e-mail, the following additional information will be collected:
The e-mail address and contents of the e-mail; and
Information volunteered in response to the survey.
The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include
audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us.
The information is retained in accordance with Government Code §
11015.5.
If You Send Us an Email
You may choose to provide us with personal information, as in e-mail with
a comment or question. We use the information to improve our service to
you or to respond to your request. Sometimes we forward your e-mail to
other State employees who may be better able to help you, and this staff
may be employed by a different agency within the State. Except for authorized
law enforcement investigations or, as required by law, we do not share
our e-mail with any other organizations.
We use your e-mail to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to
you, to address issues you identify, to further improve our web site, or
to forward the e-mail to another agency for appropriate action.
Order Forms
If you place an order with us, we request information from the user on
our order form. A user must provide contact information (like name and
shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number and
expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to
fill your order/request. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact
information is used to get in touch with you.
Public Disclosure
In the State of California, laws exist to ensure that government is open
and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information
possessed by State government. At the same time, there are exceptions to
the public's right to access public records. These exceptions serve various
needs including maintaining the privacy of individuals. Both State and
federal laws provide exceptions.
All information collected at this site becomes public record that may
be subject to inspection and copying by the public, unless an exemption
in law exists. In the event of a conflict between this Use Policy and the
Public Records Act, the Information Practices Act, or other law governing
the disclosure of records, the Public Records Act, the Information Practices
Act, or other applicable law will control.
Automatic Collection of Information/Cookies
Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by your web browser.
The main State portal does not use cookies to maintain personalization,
however some departmental applications may.
The State makes every attempt to avoid the use of cookies. When needed
to maintain the functionality of an application, unlike the common usage
of cookies, the State only uses cookies during the session in which you
access our interactive applications.
Cookies created on your computer by using this web site do not contain
"personal
information" and do not compromise your privacy or security. We use
the cookie feature only to store a randomly generated identifying temporary
tag on your computer. You can refuse the cookie or delete the cookie file
from your computer by using any of the widely available methods. However,
if you turn your cookie option off, you may not be able to access some
of the features in our interactive applications.
Security
The State, as developer and manager of this web site, has taken several
steps to safeguard the integrity of its telecommunications and computing
infrastructure, including but not limited to authentication, monitoring,
auditing, and encryption. Security measures have been integrated into the
design, implementation, and day-to-day practices of the entire State operating
environment as part of its continuing commitment to risk management. This
information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal,
or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information
provided via the State's supported web site. The technical standards governing
security are enforced by the Department of Finance.
Links to Other Sites
Our web site has links to sites we feel might be useful to you and which
may provide services. When you link to another site, you are no longer
on our site and are subject to the privacy policy of the new site.
This web site and the information it contains are provided as a public
service by the State of California. This system is monitored to ensure
proper operation, to verify the functioning of applicable security features,
and for comparable purposes. Anyone using this system expressly consents
to such monitoring. Unauthorized attempts to modify any information stored
on this system, to defeat or circumvent security features, or to utilize
this system for other than its intended purposes are prohibited and may
result in criminal prosecution.
Limitation of Liability
The State attempts to maintain the highest accuracy of content on its
web site. Any errors or omissions should be reported for investigation.
The State makes no claims, promises, or guarantees about the absolute
accuracy, completeness, or adequacy of the contents of this web site and
expressly disclaims liability for errors and omissions in the contents
of this web site. No warranty of any kind, implied, expressed, or statutory,
including but not limited to the warranties of non-infringement of third
party rights, title, merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose,
and freedom from computer virus, is given with respect to the contents
of this web site or its hyperlinks to other Internet resources. Reference
in this web site to any specific commercial products, processes, or services,
or the use of any trade, firm, or corporation name is for the information
and convenience of the public, and does not constitute endorsement, recommendation,
or favoring by the State of California, or its employees or agents.
This Use Policy is subject to change without notice.
Ownership
In general, information presented on this web site, unless otherwise indicated,
is considered in the public domain. It may be distributed or copied as
permitted by law. However, the State does make use of copyrighted data
(e.g., photographs) which may require additional permissions prior to your
use. In order to use any information on this web site not owned or created
by the State, you must seek permission directly from the owning (or holding)
sources. The State shall have the unlimited right to use for any purpose,
free of any charge, all information submitted via this site except those
submissions made under separate legal contract. The State shall be free
to use, for any purpose, any ideas, concepts, or techniques contained in
information provided through this site.
